<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Holden Lee's Website</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Holden Lee</name>
        <email>oldheneel@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2017-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>General advice</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/General%20advice.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/General%20advice.html</id>
    <published>2017-11-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> General advice </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-11-18 
          , Modified: 2017-11-18 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/advice.html">advice</a>, <a href="/tags/life.html">life</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"> <ul>
 <li><a href="#links">Links</a></li>
 </ul> </div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>Read. You can’t count on others to tell you what to read. There are many books I’ve read that changed my views that I wished I’d read earlier. Reading for pleasure is good, but also read strategically. Go out of your way to figure out a list of books that are important and for what reasons, and read some of them. Sometimes adults will just tell you to read, but not try and pick the best books for you to read. In particular, adults have a tendency to just push story-books they feel are age-appropriate. Read nonfiction, or fiction with Views. Don’t believe what you read. Read things you disagree with. Read Ayn Rand and Karl Marx, and then form your own opinion. Especially read about big ideas. Read life advice by successful people. Your brain will feel exploded afterwards, and you’ll feel paralyzed for a while afterwards (if you’re anything like me), so maybe don’t do this too often, but you want to know all your options and possible strategies early. Find things to follow, like blogs with ideas, debates. You don’t have to follow them consistently - I regularly go for extended periods where I consume little media, because that makes it easier to focus - but know they’re there.</p>
<p>Strategize your distractions. It’s hard to be productive every minute - and distractions smoothen life out. The key is to have high-quality distractions. Ex. reddit front page rarely has anything meaningful, you could instead look at subreddits that pertain to your interest. Find the distractions that are meaningful to you, like webcomics and blogs. These are high-quality distractions. Low-quality distractions are things like checking your email every few minutes.</p>
<p>Your job isn’t to know what you want to do: it’s to get yourself exposed to interesting things, to things that are beautiful and to things that give you power (ex. knowledge).</p>
<p>Develop taste. Don’t just do things. Don’t just play computer games. If you like computer games, play good computer games. Find the games that have really creative storytelling, or really good mechanics, or are revolutionary in some way.</p>
<p>Do projects. Have experience in coming up with an idea or initiative you want to pursue, and then pursuing it - rather than just doing something someone told you to do.</p>
<p>Develop a love for learning. A love for learning means you’ll learn, even when no one recognizes you for it - when you don’t win competitions, when you don’t get certificates or badges. Some people were born with this love; some had it instilled in them from their family or community. But even if you haven’t, you can still develop it. It’s not easy. Pride is dangerous: beware of taking too much pleasure in doing something well. A litmus test is would you still do it if you didn’t get the recognition? Many people hit a wall in college: they didn’t realize all the hidden motivations that compelled them to learn (ex. being better than other people), and these motivations dry up (ex. they are suddenly not better than everyone else around them). The solution is to have motivations to learn that won’t dry up. Find them. It’s fine to be motivated by pride and competition - but make sure you have something more substantial to lean on. Get off your crutches early. Know that love for learning often doesn’t come automatically, but it is a very rewarding thing to develop.</p>
<p>Learn different things. You don’t have to cover everything - you can’t cover everything. But learn different things. The first step in learning something, unless you have a good sense of it already, is not to pick a random textbook and start reading. People are passionate about subjects for a reason - figure out what it is that makes them tick. Figure out what is “good work” in the subject. Figure out what are the books, classes, exercises, and projects that will help you learn the subject, based on your experience. This used to be much harder, but now there’s the Internet. There are many recommendations online, many online courses and course materials to pursue. Sometimes the official sources - ex. textbooks - are hard to penetrate. Find other sources - blog posts, videos, whatever. There are many roads. Don’t dismiss entire subjects as “not interesting.” You can dismiss them as “not my focus right now.” Think of every subject and contemplate on it a little. What are the “classics”? Why do people study them? Ask these questions. Figure out why these subjects are interesting, why they are worth learning, and then you can make your decisions on what to focus on learning. It’s much, much easier to explore things earlier than later. When your interests change, don’t force them to stay on the same track. Keep your life plans flexible. When you have doubts about whether you want to do X or Y, remember that doubts grow when suppressed. Doubts want to either annihilate the object of doubt, or be annihilated. So try out that other thing, and you’ll know which is the outcome. Either is better than suppressed doubt.</p>
<p>Write everything down. Figure out (after some experimentation) a consistent way to take notes so that you can search up anything important you’ve ever learned. (I recommend <a href="https://workflowy.com/invite/fdc650b.lnx">workflowy</a> or <a href="https://dynalist.io/invite/6Chr2g">dynalist</a>, but there are many options: OneNote, EverNote, etc.) You can learn things halfway and then pick up where you left off. “Disorganization” is not a unchangeable trait. Fix it. People underutilize the organizational and remembering power of computers, or even paper and pencil. Carry a notebook, and write down things to remember. Don’t just absorb and copy. Write things in your own words. Write down your questions. Questions are the knives that cut through the curtain of life. Find opportunities to ask the questions that you write down. Write down the answers when you find them.</p>
<h2 id="links">Links</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/hs.html">What you’ll wish you’d known, Paul Graham</a> (see also <a href="https://www.quora.com/How-can-one-be-academically-successful-in-high-school-What-might-one-regret-not-doing-while-in-high-school-What-are-some-general-tips-you-would-give-to-somebody-to-have-the-best-academic-experience-possible/answer/Qiaochu-Yuan-1">Qiaochu’s answer</a>)</li>
<li><a href="https://putanumonit.com/2017/10/11/winning-is-for-losers/">Winning is for losers, Jacob Falkovich</a></li>
<li><a href="http://theamericanscholar.org/the-disadvantages-of-an-elite-education/">Disadvantages of an elite education</a></li>
</ul>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Surrounded by music</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Surrounded%20by%20music.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Surrounded%20by%20music.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Surrounded by music </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-18 
          , Modified: 2017-08-18 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/music.html">music</a>, <a href="/tags/art.html">art</a>, <a href="/tags/teach_kid.html">teach_kid</a>, <a href="/tags/teaching.html">teaching</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Music.html">Music</a>, <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>A conversation between friends.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>J: I want my kids to be surrounded by music.</p>
<p>M: That’s easy - just give them iPods!</p>
<p>J: No, I don’t mean that… I want them to be banging on pots and pans.</p>
</blockquote>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Forget your index cards</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Forget%20your%20index%20cards.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Forget%20your%20index%20cards.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Forget your index cards </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-18 
          , Modified: 2017-08-18 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/index%20cards.html">index cards</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>Make lots of <a href="index%20cards.html">index cards</a>, and then forget them.</p>
<p>Index cards are pensieves. They will remember for you, even when you forget.</p>
<p>If you keep them in mind at all times, you’re holding many little stones, and don’t have the space to come up with new things.</p>
<p>A musician learns music theory in order to compose and play well, but doesn’t think about it consciously in the actual act of playing.</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Bite-sized writing for powerful thinking</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Bite-sized%20writing%20for%20powerful%20thinking.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Bite-sized%20writing%20for%20powerful%20thinking.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-18T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-18T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Bite-sized writing for powerful thinking </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-18 
          , Modified: 2017-08-18 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/index%20cards.html">index cards</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"> <ul>
 <li><a href="#warm-up">Warm-up</a></li>
 <li><a href="#models-of-writing">Models of writing</a><ul>
 <li><a href="#model-1">Model 1</a></li>
 <li><a href="#model-2">Model 2</a></li>
 <li><a href="#comparison">Comparison</a></li>
 <li><a href="#aside-english-class">Aside: English class</a></li>
 </ul></li>
 <li><a href="#how-to-have-ideas">How to have ideas</a><ul>
 <li><a href="#but-i-dont-have-anything-worth-writing-down">But I don’t have anything worth writing down!</a></li>
 <li><a href="#index-cards-as-pensieves">Index cards as pensieves</a></li>
 <li><a href="#system">System</a></li>
 <li><a href="#exercise">Exercise</a></li>
 </ul></li>
 <li><a href="#how-to-write-well">How to write well</a><ul>
 <li><a href="#the-inversion-heuristic">The inversion heuristic</a></li>
 <li><a href="#exercise-1">Exercise</a></li>
 </ul></li>
 <li><a href="#conclusion">Conclusion</a><ul>
 <li><a href="#moonwalking-with-einstein">Moonwalking with Einstein</a></li>
 <li><a href="#writing-for-all-aspects-of-life">Writing for all aspects of life</a></li>
 </ul></li>
 <li><a href="#other-references-and-links">Other references and links</a></li>
 </ul> </div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>Note: This is a loose transcript of a course for <a href="https://espr-camp.org/">ESPR 2017</a>, hence the colloquial/oral style.</p>
<h2 id="warm-up">Warm-up</h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>Look at several pieces of writing from this <a href="http://tiny.cc/espric">list</a>.</li>
<li>Answer these questions:
<ol type="1">
<li>What are features of “this kind of writing”?</li>
<li>How would you go about writing “this kind of writing”?</li>
</ol></li>
</ol>
<h2 id="models-of-writing">Models of writing</h2>
<h3 id="model-1">Model 1</h3>
<p>You might have a model of writing that looks something like this. You get an assignment from language class: write an essay about a certain topic. Then you sit down,</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>think very hard to come up with some thoughts, and</li>
<li>work really hard to write it all down, and</li>
<li>it doesn’t look so good, so you dress it and make the sentences more eloquent.</li>
</ol>
<p>Finally you finish and turn it in and don’t think about it until you get back your paper.</p>
<p>PICTURE</p>
<p>In summary, the model is</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>You have an idea or purpose in your head.</li>
<li>You write down the idea and dress it up.</li>
</ol>
<p>This isn’t how most writing works (in the real world)!</p>
<!--You might think that writing is a long difficult thing, and you wouldn't want to do it outside of English class.-->
<h3 id="model-2">Model 2</h3>
<p>Here’s an alternate model of writing.</p>
<ul>
<li>You have a bit of an idea in your head.</li>
<li>You write it down - it’s a small idea, so it’s just a sentence or two.</li>
<li>Later, you have another idea.</li>
<li>You write the idea down.</li>
<li>After a while, you look at your writing, and because paper has more memory than your head, you see connections between ideas and they “glom” together into a larger idea. You see that some ideas are wrong, and replace them with correct ones. You have improved ideas in your head.</li>
<li>You go back and forth between more accurate or beautiful thoughts, and clearer and more compelling writing.</li>
<li>At the end, you have these clusters of ideas, and you want to tell other people about them. You arrange these ideas, adds some section headers and some connecting bits, and you’ve finished an essay, or maybe a book.</li>
</ul>
<p>PICTURE</p>
<h3 id="comparison">Comparison</h3>
<p>Let’s compare the two models.</p>
<ul>
<li>In the previous model, you get an idea (no matter whether it’s good or bad), write it all out, and <em>then</em> try to make the writing good. Here, the process of building ideas and writing are tightly linked.</li>
<li>In either model, writing takes work. But instead of being this big difficult thing, you can view writing as an incremental thing where work feels more spread out, where every step feels more natural and yummy.</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="aside-english-class">Aside: English class</h3>
<p>I want to put this in the perspective of English (or language arts) class. English class made me confused about writing. See <a href="The%20beauty%20of%20ideas%20vs%20the%20beauty%20of%20writing.html">The beauty of ideas vs the beauty of writing</a>.</p>
<p>Writing isn’t just for academics. You can write the ideas that come to you in daily life.</p>
<h2 id="how-to-have-ideas">How to have ideas</h2>
<h3 id="but-i-dont-have-anything-worth-writing-down">But I don’t have anything worth writing down!</h3>
<p>Who writes posts on facebook? Or any words on social media?</p>
<p>You are writers (maybe not good, or long-form writers, but writers nonetheless). You have things that you want to tell your friends, stories or activities you want to share - you just don’t associate your thoughts with things that are written down, or the things that are written down with “writing” which may seem reserved for something serious and academic. And if you don’t think of your thoughts as worth recording, they can slip by and you can forget them.</p>
<p>I’ve had people tell me they’re not good at writing, but when I talk to them, I have a fascinating conversation about something they’re interested in - and if I just transcribed the interview, it might need some editing, but it would be a good piece of writing.</p>
<p>People often ask writers where they get their ideas from…</p>
<p><a href="http://www.neilgaiman.com/Cool_Stuff/Essays/Essays_By_Neil/Where_do_you_get_your_ideas%3F">Neil Gaiman said</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>You get ideas from daydreaming. You get ideas from being bored. You get ideas all the time. The only difference between writers and other people is we notice when we’re doing it.</p>
<p>You get ideas when you ask yourself simple questions. The most important of the questions is just, What if…? …If only…</p>
</blockquote>
<h3 id="index-cards-as-pensieves">Index cards as pensieves</h3>
<p>In the Harry Potter world, “pensieves” are these basins you can put your memories into, so that you can review them anytime later.</p>
<p>I think this is awesome - when there’s something that you keep thinking about, or want to reference later, wouldn’t it be great if you could just capture it and put it somewhere?</p>
<p>We don’t have pensieves, but we do have writing. When you write a thought down, you can rethink it anytime without fear of forgetting it, and build on it.</p>
<p>PICTURE</p>
<p>I like to think of index cards as pensieves. They don’t have to be <em>literally</em> index cards.</p>
<p>An index card is a natural size for writing. Imagine something you would write on an index card - like Trefethen’s index cards. An index card has the feature of not being too large - there’s not much space - and the feature of being a coherent idea (or cluster of ideas).</p>
<p>Some of the examples are from Lloyd Trefethen, who wrote a lot of his thoughts on 4x6 index cards and then published around 200 into a book.</p>
<p>When you have an idea “index-carded”, you can then hold a concept clearly in your mind and easily transmit it to others with good fidelity (and they can transmit it to yet more people). Something with the size and coherence of an index card is <em>mimetic</em>.</p>
<p>Here’s an <a href="index%20cards.html">index card on index cards</a>.</p>
<h3 id="system">System</h3>
<p>In order for this model of writing to work, you need a notetaking system. I don’t mean a notetaking system in the restricted sense of taking down an hour-long lecture; I mean a system where you can easily write down your thoughts at any time.</p>
<p>The two criteria for such a system are:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>It has low activation energy.</li>
<li>It is easily searchable.</li>
</ol>
<p>You can use any notetaking framework. I recommend using <a href="https://workflowy.com/invite/fdc650b.lnx">workflowy</a> or <a href="https://dynalist.io/invite/6Chr2g">dynalist</a>. You can use a wiki, blog, or journal for writing up longer posts. When you’re out and around and you have a good idea, you can write them down on your phone or pocket notebook.</p>
<h3 id="exercise">Exercise</h3>
<p>Come up with a list of things that you want to write about. Nothing is too small. Good search terms:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Hobby, interest, topic, or activity you like, especially something that is less common.</li>
<li>Things that you keep coming back to - things you want to pensieve.</li>
<li>Personal philosophy - what’s a way you look at the world that’s unique to you?</li>
<li>Thing that happened to you, that tickled you in some way.</li>
<li>What do you want to communicate to people? If you could give everyone in the world (or your community) an index card, what would be on it?</li>
<li>A book/movie/etc. you like. A person you admire. What are the key ideas or qualities?</li>
<li>Things you like to tell other people in conversation</li>
</ol>
<p>Note that Trefethen’s index cards are often about a thing that happens in daily life, plus a reflection on it. Also note how he can use an experience to define a whole category of experiences.</p>
<p>Now that we have ideas, how do we write them well?</p>
<h2 id="how-to-write-well">How to write well</h2>
<h3 id="the-inversion-heuristic">The inversion heuristic</h3>
<p>There’s a lot of specific advice out there (see for example <a href="What%20I%20learned%20from%20Patrick%20Winston.html">What I learned from Patrick Winston</a>); I’ll just give one general principle, the <strong>inversion heuristic</strong>.</p>
<p>The inversion heuristic is: Put yourself in the reader’s shoes. What do they want? How can you make the writing compelling and useful to them?</p>
<p>Taking a coarse view, there are two things (nonfiction) writing needs to do.</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Say why the topic is interesting.</li>
<li>Deliver the information so that the structure in your head becomes the structure in the reader’s head. For example, if you’re teaching someone an activity, give the the steps clearly. (Try to communicate the structure - if it’s a list, give a list. If it’s a dialogue in your head, give it as a dialogue - you aren’t constrained to a certain format, like you learn in English class. If a picture helps, draw it in.)<a href="#fn1" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref1"><sup>1</sup></a></li>
</ol>
<p>This is very similar to teaching: imagine you were learning the material for the first time - what would you want?</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>You want to know why you’d even care about the topic - why is it interesting?</li>
<li>You want clear instructions on how to do the thing.</li>
</ol>
<p>Note that many of the things that work to get better for writing or more generally communication for other people, also help even if you’re only making notes to yourself. For example, in order for your notes to help you remember your thoughts, you must write clearly; on the other hand, being concise means writing and reading doesn’t take up a lot of your time, or fill your head with irrelevant details.</p>
<p>One thing that you <em>do</em> have to do more of when writing to other people is to make a bridge - for example make them interested if they’re not already as interested as you are, and give them background they need to understand. <!--However, this can often clarify your own thinking, as often you don't truly understand something until you can explain it from scratch. --></p>
<h3 id="exercise-1">Exercise</h3>
<ol type="1">
<li>Choose one thing from your list, that you wanted to write about.</li>
<li>Pair up.</li>
<li>Interview your neighbor about their topic. Try to ask the questions so that YOU can write about it. Then write an outline. Don’t stop your line of questioning until you feel you see why their thing is interesting, and break it down into its parts.</li>
</ol>
<p>The point of the exercise is: When you’re writing by yourself, you will be your own critic, imagining yourself as a reader who needs to be convinced and taught. That’s a skill to be developed, so here, you have someone else to be a critic.</p>
<p>You want your writing to be compelling, and the arguments to follow naturally. Writing your own ideas, you may miss something that you think is “obvious”, or assume the reader already thinks the material is interesting or conceptualizes it in a similar way as you. Or you may have cached an argument that you’ve heard and are just repeating it without thinking it through. Eventually, you want to be your own critic in terms of exposing these gaps. Finding these gaps is useful not just for communicating to others, it can help you realize there were gaps in your knowledge and improve your conception of the idea!</p>
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>
<h3 id="moonwalking-with-einstein">Moonwalking with Einstein</h3>
<p>In <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6346975-moonwalking-with-einstein?ac=1&amp;from_search=true">Moonwalking with Einstein</a>, the author talks about his journey of training for the International Memory Olympiad, and on the way, gives the history of writing and the history of memorization.</p>
<p>Before the printing press, having copies of manuscripts was costly. Learned people memorized entire books in their heads, so they could conjure up the knowledge they needed anytime.</p>
<p>In the modern age, memorization can seem obsolete, because the Internet gives instant information at our fingertips. Some people worry that this has dumbed us down.</p>
<p>Joshua Foer presents the following dilemma: In this age, we read a lot of books and articles - but how much of it do we actually remember? If we didn’t remember it, what was the point of reading it?</p>
<p>One answer to this dilemma is as follows. We don’t need to memorize everything, because we have information at our fingertips - but neither are we intelligent by having Internet access alone. We are overwhelmed by that raw information. Instead, we maintain a kind of superstructure of “notes” between us and all the information out there.</p>
<p>I want to end with my conception of what being “well-read” is. It’s not sufficient to just read a bunch of books if you forget what you read. Read widely, and reflect, record, and summarize things that you read.<a href="#fn2" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref2"><sup>2</sup></a> Remember that they can be bite-sized. Index into books and articles.</p>
<h3 id="writing-for-all-aspects-of-life">Writing for all aspects of life</h3>
<p>Writing notes down, organizing, and later reflecting or expanding them is a habit that’s useful in many areas of life, and that will have more gains the more you develop it.<a href="#fn3" class="footnoteRef" id="fnref3"><sup>3</sup></a></p>
<p>Here are some examples:</p>
<ul>
<li>How many of you have gone to a talk, and felt you didn’t get anything out of it? Here’s a suggestion: try to get three things out of a talk. <a href="http://math.stanford.edu/~vakil/threethings.html">If you can get three things out of a talk, it was a successful talk.</a> Note that three things can fit on an index card.</li>
<li>This isn’t just for “rational” stuff. Artists do it too. A painter might have post-it notes all over their easel.</li>
<li>Write down concise articulation of what makes something good. I recommend the following exercise for creative writing: take some books you really like. Think about and write down what makes them <em>interesting</em> and <em>different</em>. (For example, for Lord of the Rings: It’s not a story about an ambitious person setting out to find treasure, but a story about a non-ambitious person (Hobbit) setting out to destroy treasure (the ring).)</li>
<li>Creative writing: go back and forth between exploratory writing (unstructured) and outlining (structured). See <a href="http://www.writingexcuses.com/2017/05/28/12-22-hybrid-outlining-and-discovery-writing/">here</a>. Kazuo Ishiguro talks about “bottling up” in his <a href="https://holdenlee.wordpress.com/2014/02/18/kazuo-ishiguro-on-writing/">interview</a>.</li>
<li>It’s useful to write down summaries/notes of many things, like conversations and people (Farley file).</li>
<li>How do you remember a story for storytelling (or other oral presentation)a Imagine it as a scene (like a visual index card).</li>
</ul>
<p>One thing to consider doing is to start a blog! I’m happy to help you set it up.</p>
<p>Take some index cards! Write things on them. Your mind is a net, capturing ideas as you move through the world…</p>
<p>There’s a table in the googledoc. I encourage you to post your “index cards” there. (You can also take a picture of your index card and upload it.)</p>
<h2 id="other-references-and-links">Other references and links</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://slatestarcodex.com/2016/02/20/writing-advice/">Nonfiction writing advice (Slatestarcodex)</a>: highly recommended</li>
<li><a href="https://usamo.wordpress.com/2015/03/14/writing/">Writing for thinking (Evan Chen)</a>.</li>
<li>My (very abbreviated notes) on a CFAR alumni reunion class, <a href="https://workflowy.com/s/BeBJ.lb28OIC55u">Notetaking 101: Growing an exobrain (Joel Solymosi)</a>.
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.abc.net.au/radionational/programs/philosopherszone/the-extended-mind/2986780">The extended mind</a>.</li>
</ul></li>
<li><a href="What%20I%20learned%20from%20Patrick%20Winston.html">What I learned from Patrick Winston</a>.</li>
</ul>
<!--
* [Notes on writing about books](https://holdenlee.wordpress.com/2015/03/22/notes-on-writing-about-books/): my suggestions on writing about books
-->
<section class="footnotes">
<hr />
<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>Minsky does this, e.g. in <a href="https://web.media.mit.edu/~minsky/Introduction.html">The Emotion Machine</a>. Here is one article I wrote as a conversation: <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Conversation%20on%20curiosity.html">Conversation on curiosity</a>.<a href="#fnref1">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>See my <a href="https://holdenlee.wordpress.com/2015/03/22/notes-on-writing-about-books/">suggestions on writing about books</a>.<a href="#fnref2">↩</a></p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>One warning: when you’ve written too much, it can be easy to get sucked into reviewing your writing. <a href="Forget%20your%20index%20cards.html">Forget your index cards</a><a href="#fnref3">↩</a></p></li>
</ol>
</section>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>X vs Myopic X</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/X%20vs%20Myopic%20X.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/X%20vs%20Myopic%20X.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> X vs Myopic X </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/Ayn%20Rand.html">Ayn Rand</a>, <a href="/tags/creativity.html">creativity</a>, <a href="/tags/egotism.html">egotism</a>, <a href="/tags/flaws.html">flaws</a>, <a href="/tags/goals.html">goals</a>, <a href="/tags/love.html">love</a>, <a href="/tags/myopia.html">myopia</a>, <a href="/tags/remix.html">remix</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>The myopic x problem is the problem where I’m motivated by x, but I <em>cling</em> to x, and won’t do things that help me achieve x if they involve stepping outside of x for a moment. So being myopically x hinders my accomplishing x. I have the myopic egotism problem: when becoming a better person (ultimate goal is egotistic) means forgetting myself and being open and listening to other people (which involves temporarily suspending egotism), I have trouble. The myopic creativity problem is when I put myself in front of an empty screen and try to write, when coming up with something to write involves reading, watching, and studying books/movies/etc., talking to and doing things with people, and learning more about the world. Myopic egotism and myopic creativity together make me think everything I do should come from myself, and prevent me from “standing on the shoulders of giants.”</p>
<p>(On friendship and love I think I have the opposite problem: I’m farsighted, looking in the distance, wanting these connections because of the benefits they will bring, rather than wanting them in themselves. I.e. learning:creating::friendship:(everything friendship leads to), where I’m myopic in the second component, so I overlook the first. As a contrast, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13037.Justine">Justine</a> is about myopic love.</p>
<p>The thing with ulterior motives (do A in order to B) is that although I can’t deny their existence, I have to get myself to <em>not think about</em> B and get myself to <em>truly love</em> A. The only way to truly be knowledgeable is to love learning; the only way to truly enrich myself is to cultivate love and friendship, without thinking of these as for the ulterior purpose of cultivating myself.)</p>
<p>It’s the same with research: I spend too much time trying to get an idea to work, so I can publish it and Have Done Something New! when instead I should ask myself things like, is this likely to work? what’s the best use of time? what things should I understand better before I try to come up with something new? what foundational things should I be learning?</p>
<p><a href="http://lesswrong.com/lw/oh/righting_a_wrong_question/">Why do I think</a> this is circular? Because I think, “once I create something truly new, then I’ll have the confidence that I’m not just a rehash, and then I can go out and learn stuff without worrying whether I can be original.” This means that I shouldn’t change my current course—I should keep spending a lot of my effort on creating, rather than putting the creating aside. The circularity comes from (1) creating requires me to learn/absorb stuff, (2) I don’t want to learn/absorb a lot of stuff until I’ve proved that I can create something.</p>
<p>The myopic creativity that I’m talking about, I think, is a bastardized version of what an artist would call “creativity.” <a href="http://www.brainpickings.org/index.php/2011/08/01/networked-knowledge-combinatorial-creativity/">A lot of creativity is remix</a>. It’s being “my brain is open”: not a flow of information <em>out</em>, but a flow of information <em>in</em>. I try to tell myself that life is remix. But I have a hard time having faith in it.</p>
<p>The catch-22 is illusory though. (1) is true regardless of whether I want to believe it or not. (2) is in my head: it’s a “want” not a “need.” (Like men saying they have to “satisfy their needs,” ugh.)</p>
<p>How is this related to Ayn Rand style egoism? I like her teachings. But I think one has to be very careful because the idea of egoism is easy to misinterpret. It’s easy to <a href="http://english.stackexchange.com/questions/7482/whats-the-difference-between-egotism-and-egoism">confuse egoism and egotism</a>; I use “egotism” to refer to “myopic egoism.” Egoism, done right, includes a (sometimes difficult) realization that even when the end goal is benefiting yourself, you’ll have to step outside yourself to accomplish it—you’ll need your friends’ help, you’ll need to be humble and learn from the masters. Egotism is refusing to step outside yourself for even a moment, and it remains egotism even if you try to label it “egoism.”</p>
<p>The essay <a href="http://lesswrong.com/lw/os/joy_in_discovery/">Joy in Discovery</a>: that’s exactly the attitude I need to have. This reminds me of another Ayn Rand bit: she always says that when you enjoy something, that pleasure is <em>yours</em>. She affirms that [the way you relate to something making you happy] cannot be taken away from you. So even if you’re not a good painter at all, and you don’t own any works of art, you can walk in the museum and get a <em>uniquely personal experience</em>.</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>What writers want</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/What%20writers%20want.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/What%20writers%20want.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> What writers want </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/writing.html">writing</a>, <a href="/tags/desire.html">desire</a>, <a href="/tags/quote.html">quote</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Writing.html">Writing</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <blockquote>
<p>“An artist does not live a personal life as we do, he hides it, forcing us to go to his books if we wish to touch the true source of his feelings… Underneath all his preoccupations with sex, society, religion, etc. there is, quite simple, a man tortured beyond endurance by the lack of tenderness in the world.” –Justine, Lawrence Durrell</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Writers want people to talk after reading their writing. Not simply about style—though that is interesting and helpful—but thoughts more spiritual in nature. What did the reader think about after reading? It doesn’t even have to be related. Just say what you think about… because people rarely say what they think about.</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Understanding between sexual cultures</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Understanding%20between%20sexual%20cultures.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Understanding%20between%20sexual%20cultures.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Understanding between sexual cultures </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/culture.html">culture</a>, <a href="/tags/LGBT.html">LGBT</a>, <a href="/tags/sexuality.html">sexuality</a>, <a href="/tags/understanding.html">understanding</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>Update: <a href="http://rationallyspeakingpodcast.org/show/rs-187-jason-weeden-on-do-people-vote-based-on-self-interest.html">Jason Weeden</a> gave an interesting interview discussing “ring-bearers” and “free-wheelers”.</p>
<p>I feel that a lot can be solved if people have the right attitude (meta-moral sense?). Trying to understand each other. Rather than having a foundational goal to draw a dividing line between oneself and others (it’s amazing how many actions can be traced back to that “tribal” motivation), seek to understand each other and both better your own life and other people’s. I think if you replace these foundational goals, the justification for certain actions melts away.</p>
<p>A lot of it comes back to what Karen Armstrong said about jihadists. If people feel their belief system, their values, their community is being threatened, they will go on the offensive. It’s human nature. Someone has to break the cycle, and try to understand the other side even as the other side is throwing words, or worse, sticks and stones, at you.</p>
<p>One place where this is especially true is in sexuality. On the one side are conservative people (sex after marriage, man and woman, etc.). On another are LGBTP people (P=poly), or people who promote a more open sexual culture (a la Stranger in a Strange Land). And there are people who participate in the “casual hookup culture.” Of course, there are many shades of gray in between.</p>
<p>So let’s look at the web of threats. LGBTP people are threatened by the conservative people—it’s hard to talk with someone who thinks it’s a moral sin (go to hell) for you to have the sexual identity that you have! Conservative people are threatened by the increasing number of people who participate in the “casual hookup culture.” It’s been flipped from 100 years ago, that believing in sex after marriage can actually make you part of the minority, and disparagingly called a “prude.” They feel threatened by sexual jokes that people make to them, and lewd behavior in public. (Brave New World shows this by taking it to the extreme: what if you are the ONLY person who believes in committed monogamy?) (And it’s complicated: people will claim they have the freedom to do what they want, which is true, but with freedom comes the responsibility to use the freedom wisely. Just because you <em>can</em> eat steak in front of a vegetarian, doesn’t mean you should.) The people who participate in casual hookup culture feel threatened by the conservatives: this is the kind of prudishness that they’re trying to escape. The conservatives feel threatened by the LGBTP people because they go against religious teachings. This last link is flawed though—if these conservative people remove their “tribal” motivation and allow their opinion to be changed, then it’s pretty clear that what they are rebelling against is the loss of family values—where freed from the Bible’s word, family should have a more abstract interpretation as a cohesive, symbiotic community unit—and then they should <strong>look for evidence</strong> for or against LGBTP relationships meeting that criteria (and the evidence is overwhelming for the fact that they can meet that criteria).</p>
<p>I think we need to draw the line between what a person believes in, and what’s universal. What’s universal here is wanting to be happy, have some kind of stability in life, having good relationships with other people, protecting from disease (which is actually very important here—and a fact that has been disguised. rather than standing on its own as a goal, it’s been cited as evidence of immorality of sex. The causality is screwed up here: immorality does not cause disease!). Trying to tack more than this starts to skew this universal picture towards one’s own view. There’s the kind of person who wants to follow the traditional path of marriage, and the kind who will have flings with a lot of people. (The problem with SiaSL is that it seemed to suggest that the second option is strictly better for every person, which is untrue.) Each person has their own personal truths, but some truths are better than others. The best that these different groups can do is not to impose their worldview on each other, but to explain to people what is it that their way of life offers, to try and talk to people about the link between the universal things that they want (see above) and the sexual life that they choose. Imagine them next to each other in an activities fair. The conservative group talks about how abstinence helps one develop a strong moral fiber in the sense of “delayed gratification” being a general helpful quality to nurture in one’s life, attach more weight and meaning to one’s actions, etc. (I personally believe in sex after marriage <em>for myself</em>, and these are the terms I think in, not religious commandments.) The liberal group talks about how sexuality can be an important part of your identity as a human being, how it can be a pleasurable and healthy part of your life, etc. And what I mean by “some truths are better than others,” is that anyone can declare that they’re doing is “right, you got a problem with that?” but if you haven’t thought through these issues, and you leave behind a trail of broken hearts and find your life empty, then chances are that you should have thought things over more. I find that often the most mature views on sexuality come from the LGBTP community, just because they have had to grapple with these issues while most other people just shove them under the rug (ex. poly people talk about things like jealousy and commitment because they have to, while mono people can often have trouble even starting the conversation on these topics).</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Two kinds of laughter</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Two%20kinds%20of%20laughter.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Two%20kinds%20of%20laughter.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Two kinds of laughter </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/psychology.html">psychology</a>, <a href="/tags/society.html">society</a>, <a href="/tags/censorship.html">censorship</a>, <a href="/tags/dichotomy.html">dichotomy</a>, <a href="/tags/humor.html">humor</a>, <a href="/tags/mindfulness.html">mindfulness</a>, <a href="/tags/social.html">social</a>, <a href="/tags/socialprogramming.html">socialprogramming</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>There are two kinds of humor and laughter. It’s similar to how feedback can be positive or negative.</p>
<ul>
<li>Positive laughter opens people up to new possibilities. Good stand-up comedians make jokes that expose stereotypes about race, sex, religion, etc. and in so doing make people think, “isn’t it stupid the way things are?” and “it doesn’t have to be this way.” It’s also the laughter between friends, building positive <a href="http://ncase.me/neurons/">Hebbian connections</a> in your neurons, “I want to do this again.”</li>
<li>Negative laughter closes off possibilities. People laugh at someone who fails - and each such laugh is a censor that will prevent themselves from trying new things. Laughter in the face of an idea that someone proposes is a veto without an explanation. (And if a person introduces an idea with a laugh, it’s social insurance against the possible drop in reputation if others find it stupid, at the cost of the idea actually being considered seriously.) The quips that people in different fields make with each other are not so innocuous if they’re saying, “Your values are different from us, and I don’t think they’re as valuable as ours.”</li>
</ul>
<p>I want to make sure that every time I laugh, it’s positive laughter.</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The right movement vs the material story</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/The%20right%20movement%20vs%20the%20material%20story.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/The%20right%20movement%20vs%20the%20material%20story.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> The right movement vs the material story </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/dichotomy.html">dichotomy</a>, <a href="/tags/advice.html">advice</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>There is a tendency, after success, to exaggerate it, to focus on the quantifiables, to express it as the natural end-result or goal of optimization.</p>
<p>“You should go out, participate in lots of activities, and meet lots of people!”</p>
<p>Translation:</p>
<p>“Go out to an activity you’d like, and meet one person. Did you like that? Then repeat.”</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The heart is a lonely hunter</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/The%20heart%20is%20a%20lonely%20hunter.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/The%20heart%20is%20a%20lonely%20hunter.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> The heart is a lonely hunter </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/none.html">none</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Books.html">Books</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <h2 id="connections">Connections</h2>
<p><a href="https://workflowy.com/s/4qkO9xWz4M#/420df0d7e81a">Summary notes</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Why was it that in cases of real love the one who is left does not more often follow the beloved by suicide?… when there is love, the widowed must stay for the resurrection of the beloved - so that the one who has gone is not really dead, but grows and is created for a second time in the soul of the living. (122)</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This is a pessimistic book. It posits that people are… lonely inside. That people want things, and do not know what they want, and are always trying to satisfy these things. It posits that we have other people as keepers of our souls - essential to our happiness - and when they die or change, part of us dies as well.</p>
<p>It seems so hopeful in the middle. Mick, with her music dreams. Singer, with his happy thoughts of spending time with Antonapoulos. Copeland and Blount, with their visions of reform.</p>
<p>No one except Singer values Antonapoulos. So Singer never tells them, and no one knows who Singer hangs his heart on. And Antonapoulos means the world to Singer. He commits suicide when Antonapoulos dies. And the four people who hung their hearts on him keep on living, but seem to die a little bit.</p>
<p>It doesn’t have to be this way. A pessimistic book is not a pessimistic outlook on life, a declaration of hopelessness. But it is saying: this is a feeling, a problem that cannot be ignored. This is a quandary that humans face, over and over again. When a loved one dies, how do we keep them alive in our mind? Because how can we persist if we do not?</p>
<p>People have these wondrous, far-reaching dreams, yet they are myopic in a way. The four people hang their hearts on Singer and never ask the question: who does Singer hang his heart on? Put all four of his friends together in a room, and the atmosphere darkens, they are not friends with each other.</p>
<p>People feel ashamed of their desires because they are mysterious, seem wrong—and after a while, it is too late, it has died. Mick and Harry. Biff, who loved Mick in a way but felt it was a wrong kind of feeling, and then Mick was deadened, and Biff lost that love.</p>
<p>(It’s so interesting: Singer is named “Singer” but he is mute. His ability to listen makes him a beautiful person: other person project onto him what they want. He is the most compassionate character in the book, he “sings” the most. And yet, his heart too is a lonely hunter.)</p>
<h2 id="music">Music</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>The symphony stayed inside her always and grew little by little. The reason was this: the whole symphony was in her mind. It had to be. She had heard every note, and somewhere in the back of her mind the whole of the music was still there just as it had been played. But she could do nothing to bring it all out again. Except wait and be ready for the times when suddenly a new part came to her. Wait for it to grow like leaves grow slowly on the branches of a spring oak tree. (239)</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote>
<p>Next to music beer was best. But now no music was in her mind. That was a funny thing. It was like she was shut out from the inside room… Woolworth’s wasn’t the same as school. When she used to come home from school she felt good and was ready to start working on the music. But now she was always too tired… And she wanted to stay in the inside room but she didn’t know how. It was like the inside room was locked somewhere away from her. (350)</p>
</blockquote>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
