<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Holden Lee's Website</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/atom.xml</id>
    <author>
        <name>Holden Lee</name>
        <email>oldheneel@gmail.com</email>
    </author>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <entry>
    <title>X vs Myopic X</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/X%20vs%20Myopic%20X.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/X%20vs%20Myopic%20X.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> X vs Myopic X </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/Ayn%20Rand.html">Ayn Rand</a>, <a href="/tags/creativity.html">creativity</a>, <a href="/tags/egotism.html">egotism</a>, <a href="/tags/flaws.html">flaws</a>, <a href="/tags/goals.html">goals</a>, <a href="/tags/love.html">love</a>, <a href="/tags/myopia.html">myopia</a>, <a href="/tags/remix.html">remix</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>The myopic x problem is the problem where I’m motivated by x, but I <em>cling</em> to x, and won’t do things that help me achieve x if they involve stepping outside of x for a moment. So being myopically x hinders my accomplishing x. I have the myopic egotism problem: when becoming a better person (ultimate goal is egotistic) means forgetting myself and being open and listening to other people (which involves temporarily suspending egotism), I have trouble. The myopic creativity problem is when I put myself in front of an empty screen and try to write, when coming up with something to write involves reading, watching, and studying books/movies/etc., talking to and doing things with people, and learning more about the world. Myopic egotism and myopic creativity together make me think everything I do should come from myself, and prevent me from “standing on the shoulders of giants.”</p>
<p>(On friendship and love I think I have the opposite problem: I’m farsighted, looking in the distance, wanting these connections because of the benefits they will bring, rather than wanting them in themselves. I.e. learning:creating::friendship:(everything friendship leads to), where I’m myopic in the second component, so I overlook the first. As a contrast, <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/13037.Justine">Justine</a> is about myopic love.</p>
<p>The thing with ulterior motives (do A in order to B) is that although I can’t deny their existence, I have to get myself to <em>not think about</em> B and get myself to <em>truly love</em> A. The only way to truly be knowledgeable is to love learning; the only way to truly enrich myself is to cultivate love and friendship, without thinking of these as for the ulterior purpose of cultivating myself.)</p>
<p>It’s the same with research: I spend too much time trying to get an idea to work, so I can publish it and Have Done Something New! when instead I should ask myself things like, is this likely to work? what’s the best use of time? what things should I understand better before I try to come up with something new? what foundational things should I be learning?</p>
<p><a href="http://lesswrong.com/lw/oh/righting_a_wrong_question/">Why do I think</a> this is circular? Because I think, “once I create something truly new, then I’ll have the confidence that I’m not just a rehash, and then I can go out and learn stuff without worrying whether I can be original.” This means that I shouldn’t change my current course—I should keep spending a lot of my effort on creating, rather than putting the creating aside. The circularity comes from (1) creating requires me to learn/absorb stuff, (2) I don’t want to learn/absorb a lot of stuff until I’ve proved that I can create something.</p>
<p>The myopic creativity that I’m talking about, I think, is a bastardized version of what an artist would call “creativity.” <a href="http://www.brainpickings.org/index.php/2011/08/01/networked-knowledge-combinatorial-creativity/">A lot of creativity is remix</a>. It’s being “my brain is open”: not a flow of information <em>out</em>, but a flow of information <em>in</em>. I try to tell myself that life is remix. But I have a hard time having faith in it.</p>
<p>The catch-22 is illusory though. (1) is true regardless of whether I want to believe it or not. (2) is in my head: it’s a “want” not a “need.” (Like men saying they have to “satisfy their needs,” ugh.)</p>
<p>How is this related to Ayn Rand style egoism? I like her teachings. But I think one has to be very careful because the idea of egoism is easy to misinterpret. It’s easy to <a href="http://english.stackexchange.com/questions/7482/whats-the-difference-between-egotism-and-egoism">confuse egoism and egotism</a>; I use “egotism” to refer to “myopic egoism.” Egoism, done right, includes a (sometimes difficult) realization that even when the end goal is benefiting yourself, you’ll have to step outside yourself to accomplish it—you’ll need your friends’ help, you’ll need to be humble and learn from the masters. Egotism is refusing to step outside yourself for even a moment, and it remains egotism even if you try to label it “egoism.”</p>
<p>The essay <a href="http://lesswrong.com/lw/os/joy_in_discovery/">Joy in Discovery</a>: that’s exactly the attitude I need to have. This reminds me of another Ayn Rand bit: she always says that when you enjoy something, that pleasure is <em>yours</em>. She affirms that [the way you relate to something making you happy] cannot be taken away from you. So even if you’re not a good painter at all, and you don’t own any works of art, you can walk in the museum and get a <em>uniquely personal experience</em>.</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Understanding between sexual cultures</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Understanding%20between%20sexual%20cultures.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Understanding%20between%20sexual%20cultures.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Understanding between sexual cultures </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/culture.html">culture</a>, <a href="/tags/LGBT.html">LGBT</a>, <a href="/tags/sexuality.html">sexuality</a>, <a href="/tags/understanding.html">understanding</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/index.html">index</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>Update: <a href="http://rationallyspeakingpodcast.org/show/rs-187-jason-weeden-on-do-people-vote-based-on-self-interest.html">Jason Weeden</a> gave an interesting interview discussing “ring-bearers” and “free-wheelers”.</p>
<p>I feel that a lot can be solved if people have the right attitude (meta-moral sense?). Trying to understand each other. Rather than having a foundational goal to draw a dividing line between oneself and others (it’s amazing how many actions can be traced back to that “tribal” motivation), seek to understand each other and both better your own life and other people’s. I think if you replace these foundational goals, the justification for certain actions melts away.</p>
<p>A lot of it comes back to what Karen Armstrong said about jihadists. If people feel their belief system, their values, their community is being threatened, they will go on the offensive. It’s human nature. Someone has to break the cycle, and try to understand the other side even as the other side is throwing words, or worse, sticks and stones, at you.</p>
<p>One place where this is especially true is in sexuality. On the one side are conservative people (sex after marriage, man and woman, etc.). On another are LGBTP people (P=poly), or people who promote a more open sexual culture (a la Stranger in a Strange Land). And there are people who participate in the “casual hookup culture.” Of course, there are many shades of gray in between.</p>
<p>So let’s look at the web of threats. LGBTP people are threatened by the conservative people—it’s hard to talk with someone who thinks it’s a moral sin (go to hell) for you to have the sexual identity that you have! Conservative people are threatened by the increasing number of people who participate in the “casual hookup culture.” It’s been flipped from 100 years ago, that believing in sex after marriage can actually make you part of the minority, and disparagingly called a “prude.” They feel threatened by sexual jokes that people make to them, and lewd behavior in public. (Brave New World shows this by taking it to the extreme: what if you are the ONLY person who believes in committed monogamy?) (And it’s complicated: people will claim they have the freedom to do what they want, which is true, but with freedom comes the responsibility to use the freedom wisely. Just because you <em>can</em> eat steak in front of a vegetarian, doesn’t mean you should.) The people who participate in casual hookup culture feel threatened by the conservatives: this is the kind of prudishness that they’re trying to escape. The conservatives feel threatened by the LGBTP people because they go against religious teachings. This last link is flawed though—if these conservative people remove their “tribal” motivation and allow their opinion to be changed, then it’s pretty clear that what they are rebelling against is the loss of family values—where freed from the Bible’s word, family should have a more abstract interpretation as a cohesive, symbiotic community unit—and then they should <strong>look for evidence</strong> for or against LGBTP relationships meeting that criteria (and the evidence is overwhelming for the fact that they can meet that criteria).</p>
<p>I think we need to draw the line between what a person believes in, and what’s universal. What’s universal here is wanting to be happy, have some kind of stability in life, having good relationships with other people, protecting from disease (which is actually very important here—and a fact that has been disguised. rather than standing on its own as a goal, it’s been cited as evidence of immorality of sex. The causality is screwed up here: immorality does not cause disease!). Trying to tack more than this starts to skew this universal picture towards one’s own view. There’s the kind of person who wants to follow the traditional path of marriage, and the kind who will have flings with a lot of people. (The problem with SiaSL is that it seemed to suggest that the second option is strictly better for every person, which is untrue.) Each person has their own personal truths, but some truths are better than others. The best that these different groups can do is not to impose their worldview on each other, but to explain to people what is it that their way of life offers, to try and talk to people about the link between the universal things that they want (see above) and the sexual life that they choose. Imagine them next to each other in an activities fair. The conservative group talks about how abstinence helps one develop a strong moral fiber in the sense of “delayed gratification” being a general helpful quality to nurture in one’s life, attach more weight and meaning to one’s actions, etc. (I personally believe in sex after marriage <em>for myself</em>, and these are the terms I think in, not religious commandments.) The liberal group talks about how sexuality can be an important part of your identity as a human being, how it can be a pleasurable and healthy part of your life, etc. And what I mean by “some truths are better than others,” is that anyone can declare that they’re doing is “right, you got a problem with that?” but if you haven’t thought through these issues, and you leave behind a trail of broken hearts and find your life empty, then chances are that you should have thought things over more. I find that often the most mature views on sexuality come from the LGBTP community, just because they have had to grapple with these issues while most other people just shove them under the rug (ex. poly people talk about things like jealousy and commitment because they have to, while mono people can often have trouble even starting the conversation on these topics).</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Two kinds of laughter</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Two%20kinds%20of%20laughter.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Two%20kinds%20of%20laughter.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Two kinds of laughter </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/psychology.html">psychology</a>, <a href="/tags/society.html">society</a>, <a href="/tags/censorship.html">censorship</a>, <a href="/tags/dichotomy.html">dichotomy</a>, <a href="/tags/humor.html">humor</a>, <a href="/tags/mindfulness.html">mindfulness</a>, <a href="/tags/social.html">social</a>, <a href="/tags/socialprogramming.html">socialprogramming</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>There are two kinds of humor and laughter. It’s similar to how feedback can be positive or negative.</p>
<ul>
<li>Positive laughter opens people up to new possibilities. Good stand-up comedians make jokes that expose stereotypes about race, sex, religion, etc. and in so doing make people think, “isn’t it stupid the way things are?” and “it doesn’t have to be this way.” It’s also the laughter between friends, building positive <a href="http://ncase.me/neurons/">Hebbian connections</a> in your neurons, “I want to do this again.”</li>
<li>Negative laughter closes off possibilities. People laugh at someone who fails - and each such laugh is a censor that will prevent themselves from trying new things. Laughter in the face of an idea that someone proposes is a veto without an explanation. (And if a person introduces an idea with a laugh, it’s social insurance against the possible drop in reputation if others find it stupid, at the cost of the idea actually being considered seriously.) The quips that people in different fields make with each other are not so innocuous if they’re saying, “Your values are different from us, and I don’t think they’re as valuable as ours.”</li>
</ul>
<p>I want to make sure that every time I laugh, it’s positive laughter.</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>The Buddha and the prince</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/The%20Buddha%20and%20the%20prince.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/The%20Buddha%20and%20the%20prince.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> The Buddha and the prince </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/spirituality.html">spirituality</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Personal%20bible.html">Personal bible</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>A prince agrees to meditate with a monk. At the end of the meditation session, the prince asks the monk how he sees him.</p>
<p>“You are a Buddha,” the monk said.</p>
<p>The prince was very happy: he must be great at this, if the first time he did this he was a Buddha already!&quot;</p>
<p>The monk asks the prince how he sees him.</p>
<p>“You are a piece of shit,” the prince said.</p>
<p>The prince tells his friend what happened, and the friend starts laughing.</p>
<p>“What’s so funny?”</p>
<p>“When you are Buddha, you see everything as Buddha,” his friend said, “When you are shit you see everything as shit.”</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Staring at the ceiling</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Staring%20at%20the%20ceiling.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Staring%20at%20the%20ceiling.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Staring at the ceiling </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/spirituality.html">spirituality</a>, <a href="/tags/Buddhism.html">Buddhism</a>, <a href="/tags/words.html">words</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Personal%20bible.html">Personal bible</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>(I found this on some Q/A site, like Quora or Math Stackexchange/Overflow. I can’t find it again.)</p>
<p>A professor was asked a question at a conference, and he looked up at the ceiling for ten seconds, causing significant discomfort in the audience. Then he looked back and delivered a perfect paragraph response.</p>
<p>This is important to me for many reasons that are quite personal. I often have trouble figuring out what to say around other people. I believe in taking time to figure things out. When I’m around other people I feel like I have to conform. But this story says: even when you’re around other people, you can in a sense block them out, think as you would think (which means taking 10 seconds if you need it), and the result would be better than if you tried to conform (try to give an answer right away, as everyone expects).</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Personalized spirituality</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Personalized%20spirituality.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Personalized%20spirituality.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Personalized spirituality </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/religion.html">religion</a>, <a href="/tags/personalization.html">personalization</a>, <a href="/tags/religion.html">religion</a>, <a href="/tags/spirituality.html">spirituality</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"> <ul>
 <li><a href="#religionspiritualityschooleducation">1 Religion:Spirituality::School:Education</a></li>
 <li><a href="#personalization">3 Personalization</a></li>
 <li><a href="#personal-philosophy">4 Personal philosophy</a></li>
 <li><a href="#lets-talk-about-what-god-is">5 Let’s talk about what God is</a></li>
 <li><a href="#definitions-of-words">6 Definitions of words</a></li>
 <li><a href="#summary">7 Summary</a></li>
 <li><a href="#more-random-bits">More random bits</a></li>
 </ul> </div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>A loose collection of thoughts.</p>
<h2 id="religionspiritualityschooleducation">1 Religion:Spirituality::School:Education</h2>
<p>I think that religion and education are very similar in many respects, in particular in the flaws of the established system of religion and education. It isn’t an inherent problem but rather often-found flaws in the established systems that exist today.</p>
<p>One important flaw is that of personalization. One’s relationship with a subject is a deeply personal one. In many subjects I find that there is a dividing line when I figured out why it was interesting to me; before I was just learning because I had to or thought I should, and so just stick to an official thread (ex. books, lectures) and don’t stray to explore; after I’m taking in things from a lot more sources. Personalization is MUCH MORE THAN “going at your own pace,” it’s about finding your own personal circle of reasons that you’re pursuing a subject, and the parts of it that are most important to you (developing personal taste, because taste is the same thing that determines what you like and don’t like, as well as propels your own work in the area). It’s about defining your own personal taste. It takes time to find. It’s not independent of following an official thread–often it has to be done concurrently. So what can be done is more EMPHASIS on personalization.</p>
<p>No one else can find this for you, which means that as instructors we should expose students to these reasons and perspectives, in an organized and curated fashion. (I love sites where people give a bunch of links to different things they found interesting and worth looking at, perhaps with short explanations.) In religion there is also a thread to follow, a holy text. Compare a holy text with an authoritative textbook. (Just because someone says something is “holy” doesn’t mean we can’t make comparisons with it.) Both are useful, but in learning it’s more than just the book but the web that is woven around it. When the teacher is the source of all knowledge, when the priest is the source of all knowledge, is where problems begin.</p>
<p>What teachers have is taste and judgment. If I were a math teacher I would give students more freedom in pursuing math they find interesting, but if I find them say, just making up long division problems and doing them for 100 steps, that’s like someone just making mac&amp;cheese all the time in a cooking class: I’d give them a nudge forward. Taste is hard to trust because it’s notoriously hard to pin down. The trust that you know a subject well enough so that you can guide a discussion in it rather than just give a lecture on it. The first seems to require more knowledge, but sometimes you can do it with less.</p>
<p>2 What is philosophy to me?</p>
<p>I’ve never taken an official class in it. I feel like I “do philosophy” but I don’t try to say any absolute truths about God, life, death, existence, meaning, and so forth, or try and reduce such statements to logic. Philosophy is to me, a way of organizing the information I have about the world in my brain, by drawing out general principles that apply cross-domains and trying to find analogies (and then understanding where they fall short). So for me, finding truth in life, rather than in a domain like mathematics where there is an absolute notion of correctness (see <a href="http://cheng.staff.shef.ac.uk/illogic/illogic-web.pdf">Eugenia Cheng’s article</a>) is a process of finding these kinds of principles and analogies, and the more things from different domains that corroborate it, the closer it comes to a personal truth. I’m hesitant of “absolute truth” when we’re away from the realms of science; too often people assume that when something feels very true to them it must be universal. What an atheist calls nature a Christian may call God. The different may be more intensional than extensional. (<a href="https://soundcloud.com/stateofthereunion/possibilities-of-the-stars?in=stateofthereunion/sets/travelogue#t=0:00">“The Possibilites of the Stars” from State of the Re:Union</a>)</p>
<p>So a lot of life is about expanding and contracting: taking in more information and experiences, then organizing that chaos into ourselves so we can keep on living. This is why maybe this post feels like going in circles, while I say a lot of stuff in the end it all comes down to a few things we all “knew already” (but did we really?) that everyone is different and we should appreciate that, etc. (In <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/350.Stranger_in_a_Strange_Land">Stranger in a Strange Land</a>, guns are “wrongness.”)</p>
<p>Are you claiming that you have more “taste” in religion? So (1) I’m not implying a correlation between “taste” and “superiority,” (2) this is an imperfect analogy that breaks down here (“related to” is not transitive [Write <span class="math inline">\(x \sim y\)</span> if <span class="math inline">\(d(x,y)&lt;1\)</span>. Then <span class="math inline">\(\sim\)</span> is not transitive.]). No, something that isn’t mass-produced isn’t bad. For example, if I don’t have time to do shopping every week for fresh food I just buy frozen/canned stuff, and it’s wonderful that we have modern refrigeration and food preservation, and frankly I’m glad for it because this means that I can focus more time on other things. But other people have a more fulfilling life in going to the farmer’s market every week and cooking with fresh vegetables.</p>
<h2 id="personalization">3 Personalization</h2>
<p>Bad school systems are characterized by control, sometimes by necessity. I contend that when organized religion is done badly it is because it becomes about control. Schools are notoriously bad at instilling motivation in students (individual teachers can, but NOT THE SYSTEM) it seems that often you have it already or not. Maybe the same is true of churches. They can guide you but you need already some germ of wanting to develop spiritually and morally.</p>
<p>So why can’t religion be more personalized? We all have ways which we look at different subjects, that have different meanings to us. In fact Christians say it: everyone has their own personal relationship with God. An official thread is useful, but it should never be viewed as a dictator. The Constitution tells us about the laws of the United States, but it doesn’t tell us how to decide every trial: there is much interpretation, there have to be many more laws, etc. to bridge the gap.</p>
<p>But what I mean is that religion can be MUCH MUCH more personalized, just like education can be MUCH MUCH more personalized. (Imagine a teacher sitting down with each student, what do you want to get out of the class, what is your interest in this subject? And then during class the teacher remembers all this, hey John you might be interested in this connection, Jill you might be interested in finding out more about that.) More personalization is the antithesis of “control,” which is why there is no systematic tendency towards it (Systems want to hold together, and control helps things hold together). It’s that we can take a hodgepodge of different philosophies, religious and scientific teachings, and make our own story out of it. This is why I’m an agnostic, or humanist, because I don’t find one thread that should be followed to the exclusion of others. (You need pure people, and you need people with feet on different islands.) But people who develop their own stories from a combination – there isn’t an automatic community for them to share those stories. What I think would benefit us is if we are able to talk about our base assumptions about the world, if there was an established entity that could help us share these thoughts. It’s an expanding circle: what’s closest to the traditional realm of religion are beliefs about life, death, God, afterlife, karma, etc., but imagine an expanding circle, you’ll eventually include everything else: what your family and friends mean to you, etc. Boundaries are artificial, only approximations, convenient packages for ideas, because everything is connected to everything else.</p>
<h2 id="personal-philosophy">4 Personal philosophy</h2>
<p>If you think you don’t have a personal philosophy, I want to convince you otherwise. It doesn’t have to be complicated, it doesn’t have to feel organized. Think of the quotes that inspire you, that when you saw read you stopped and had to repeat it because it just expressed perfectly something that was hazy in your mind. Think of the things you believe that few other people believe. Think of the theme songs you like. Think of the characters in stories that you identify with the most, the stories that you remember from when you were a kid, the trivial habits you have that others feel are silly but that are important to you. A friend of mine says, “we all have our personal mythologies.” I like that word, because one can think of mythology as philosophy connected to our individual feelings through story. And while myths that do exist may feel arbitrarily, if we create and pick our personal ones they won’t suffer from the same flaws. (We all have things that centralize us–story, rationality, perfection, etc.) For example, here is a story for me, which I read somewhere and has always stuck in my head.</p>
<p>Some guy was asked a question at a conference, and he looked up at the ceiling for ten seconds, causing significant discomfort in the audience. Then he looked back and delivered a perfect paragraph response.</p>
<p>This is important to me for many reasons that are quite personal. I often have trouble figuring out what to say around other people. I believe in taking time to figure things out. When I’m around other people I feel like I have to conform. But this story says: even when you’re around other people, you can in a sense block them out, think as you would think (which means taking 10 seconds if you need it), and the result would be better than if you tried to conform (try to give an answer right away, as everyone expects).</p>
<p>The Bible is full of parables, as is every other religious text. Parables are powerful. I contend that even people who don’t follow an established religion fill their minds with these kinds of things, which are the same elements that exist in religion, except in the first case the parables and quotes and habits are much more personalized. And might not we all benefit if we say, these really aren’t different? (There are <a href="http://www.yudkowsky.net/rational/the-simple-truth/">parables for rationality</a>.) Wouldn’t we all benefit if we shared these ways we thought about these things, these “hacks,” rather than put people in boxes by religion? (Deconstruct religion: it’s made of legos. Deconstruct education: it’s made of legos.)</p>
<p>(I say “wouldn’t it be better if…”, and you ask, “Where am I putting the blame on?” It’s just that culture isn’t like this. I’m personally sensitive to culture of interaction even though I don’t really understand culture. Some people are strong enough individuals that they bring their own reality distortion field into whatever culture they come into. So the first step is not to support the culture (for example, laughing may be a way to write things off as not serious, i.e., as a censor), and gravitate towards those who are closer.)</p>
<h2 id="lets-talk-about-what-god-is">5 Let’s talk about what God is</h2>
<p>On defining “God”: rationalists attack the contradictory definitions of God and offer it as proof that religious people don’t know what they’re talking about. It’s like this so that people can attach their own meanings to it. But let’s not stop at this counterattack. We ask: if it is so, then why do they not talk more about what these definitions are? Might not we gain more, rather than using the same word for different notions that are in other people’s heads, try to communicate what these different notions are, translate them into our personal languages? As humans we have an amazing ability of self-reflection: people tend to assume when they can’t explain something that it’s just something that can’t be communicated by language. But self-reflection is a skill to be developed. There’s a difference between someone who lectures and someone like Polya who sheds light on the problem-solving process. But we can’t develop such skills if we don’t attempt to engage in this discussions. (In fact, one reason the US education system is worse than the Japanese system is that there is no established culture for teachers to learn from each other through constructive criticism. So what’s lacking in spiritual development may be that there is simply no culture for us to talk about our beliefs in a way that we don’t take as personally offensive, rather than as contributing to growth. The possibility or non-possibility of debate is something that I feel very engrained in culture: you have subcultures where people take argument as constructive, vs. subcultures where people take argument as personal offense.)) (Working in subcultures vs. cultures. You can focus on aiming for a personal ideal rather than fighting the thoughts of those around you.)</p>
<h2 id="definitions-of-words">6 Definitions of words</h2>
<p>So people who are anti-religion have this argument against any kind of reasoning similar to mine. That is, religion is x and you’re trying to say we should tolerate it because religion is y. The problem is, <span class="math inline">\(x \ne y\)</span>. The boundaries as accepted by society today are this, and you want to redefine the boundaries as that. So maybe what you say is right, but it’s not about religion. In fact, you are even admitting religion is bad, by this kind of double-speak.</p>
<p>The same kind of thing can be said of other words. This is the problem with suitcase words, they can mean very different things, and they mean different things to each one of us! Similar arguments have been made for “feminism” and “communism” for example: that it’s a good thing but what it has been twisted to mean has strayed from the ideal.</p>
<p>Now one person cannot decide the meaning of a word; we can only change its meaning in our personal dictionary. A word acquires its meaning in a society. Perhaps the best thing is that whenever we have such a word in any serious discussion, we attempt to define it, if not directly (because it may be hard), by whatever method is useful. And we shouldn’t be put off by different definitions, but take each argument and discussion given the definition. But “the cure to bad science is good science, the cure to bad religion is good religion.”</p>
<p>“I’m not smart because I don’t do well in school,” is similar to the statement, “I’m not spiritual because I don’t believe in religion.”</p>
<h2 id="summary">7 Summary</h2>
<p>We all want to learn things, but school isn’t as helpful as it could be, and it doesn’t help everyone. We all want to make sense of our lives and be better people, but religion isn’t as helpful as it could be, and it doesn’t help everyone. People do things outside of school that are “learning” even though they don’t resemble what’s done in school. People do things outside of church to make sense of their lives and be better people, even though these activities seem far removed from a church service. There is a tension between an established system and individual aspirations–perhaps because no system can be utopic. But (1) can we first acknowledge the parallels between these different activities? and (2) create a culture where we can learn together, and make sense of our lives and be better people, that isn’t constrained by a rigid structure? (by making explicit things we don’t usually talk about)</p>
<p>(from 8-30-14)</p>
<p>In the hands of a skilled priest religion transcends religion. It’s not about religion, it’s about reflective storytelling. The book of Jonah: it’s really about doing something right because of the surface things, the perceived rewards, taking things for granted, rather than doing something just because it is right, even when you aren’t recognized for it. Being something on the surface, versus really being it. How you can appear to be something on the surface for years and years, and others go from not being to being truly instantly. The bible makes you think and draw connections. Literally it’s all about God but metaphorically it tells us about life. Maybe this is how every subject is. We learn something about life from learning, being the subject, and there is a standard we have to meet, but the masters of the subject really make the subject seem not about the facts, but having a metaphorical correspondence with life.</p>
<h2 id="more-random-bits">More random bits</h2>
<p>Assuming for the moment that this is a good viewpoint, why is it so hard to get these kinds of viewpoints into the general populace?</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>Can you imagine someone teaching this in school without backlash? It would be viewed as ideological. Many would disagree with this way to define “religion”. The power to define is powerful. It’s not important to redefine the word (in fact, we should probably invent a new word!), but it’s important to have a word to refer to the personalized philosophy I’m talking about.</li>
<li>Trying to teach anything that mediates between different viewpoints is hard. It’s easier (throughout history) that to spread an idea, rather than spread all the circle of arguments that led to it (for people to think through), you just take the conclusion you want and change it to mythos, and/or to write something that seems logical but is stripped off all the qualifications, all the strong counterarguments. It’s very rare in grade school to learn synthesis (university is much better), to take very different viewpoints that may each seem to declare an absolute truth (e.g. Ayn Rand, Karl Marx), suspend your disbelief for them, and then craft your own story around them. To some extent people in society don’t have the time to be so well-educated about the different perspectives on everything: can someone just give them something to believe? So one tries to write a book that mediates between perspectives, to get people to simulate each perspective, but reading something can only get you so far; thinking through and dialoguing is a “religious” activity in <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/6359293-the-case-for-god?from_search=true&amp;search_version=service">Armstrong</a>’s sense, that you get its benefits by force of habit, rather than by trying to just absorb the results (e.g. reading arguments that have already been written down).</li>
<li>Do ordinary people have the time to think? Yes they do, but how can you convince them? [And of course, this statement is itself offensive, “what, you say that I don’t think?”]</li>
<li>There are few places where people can dialogue in the Socratic sense of the term.</li>
<li>In the General question: how can you trust mythos? Once you get to some level of openness and tolerance, you’re much better off in learning, but how do you get there in the first place?</li>
<li>I very much like the idea of sensayers in <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/26114545-too-like-the-lightning?ac=1&amp;from_search=true">Too like the lightning</a>.</li>
</ol>
<p>(This unknowing is very good but it’s also a way of withdrawing from the conversation. “It’s fine to be religious, it’s fine to not be, as long as you’re compassionate!” But you have to dialogue about the reality: about how certain religions have strayed, what we can do about it, do some thoughtful judging because not all beliefs are equal… You don’t unknow for the sake of unknowing but for the sake of knowing.)</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Personal bible</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Personal%20bible.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Personal%20bible.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Personal bible </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/spirituality.html">spirituality</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: <a href="/Staring%20at%20the%20ceiling.html">Staring at the ceiling</a>, <a href="/The%20Buddha%20and%20the%20prince.html">The Buddha and the prince</a></p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"> <ul>
 <li><a href="#parables">Parables</a></li>
 </ul> </div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <h2 id="parables">Parables</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="Is%20A-Fu%20Stupid.html">Is A-Fu Stupid?</a></li>
<li><a href="Duck%20parable.html">Duck parable</a></li>
<li><a href="The%20Buddha%20and%20the%20prince.html">The Buddha and the prince</a></li>
<li><a href="Staring%20at%20the%20ceiling.html">Staring at the ceiling</a></li>
</ul>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Math notes</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Math%20notes.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Math%20notes.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Math notes </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: </p> 
       <p>Parent: </p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"> <ul>
 <li><a href="#number-theory">Number Theory</a></li>
 <li><a href="#high-school-math">High school math</a></li>
 <li><a href="#college-math">College math</a></li>
 </ul> </div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>Everything on this page is licensed under a <a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/">Creative) Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 3.0 Unported License</a>. Notes for seminars and talks are available at my blog <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/blog/notes.html" class="uri">http://holdenlee.github.io/blog/notes.html</a></p>
<p>Most of the source code is available either below or on <a href="http://github.com/holdenlee/mathnotes">github</a>. To compile the source you’ll need the <a href="https://github.com/holdenlee/templates">LaTeX template files</a> (see the readme for instructions).</p>
<p>Please do contact me if you find typos, want to help improve the notes, want source code, etc. I don’t always post/update the source code but I will if you poke me.</p>
<p><a rel="license" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/3.0/"><img alt="Creative Commons License" style="border-width:0" src="http://i.creativecommons.org/l/by-sa/3.0/88x31.png" /></a></p>
<h2 id="number-theory">Number Theory</h2>
<p>I’ve compiled all my number theory notes in the following open-source <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/agebfj7rldc9wl1/number-theory.pdf?dl=0">textbook</a>. Source code is available at the dedicated repository <a href="https://github.com/holdenlee/number-theory." class="uri">https://github.com/holdenlee/number-theory.</a> Note much of this is still pretty sketchy; I’ve extracted the more complete parts into the two documents beolow. Contributions and corrections are welcome; please email me at holdenlee@alum.mit.edu.</p>
<p>Update: General comments and updates are recorded on this <a href="http://goo.gl/JXBHHS">googledoc</a>.</p>
<ul>
<li>Proof of prime number theorem for arithmetic progressions: <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/zf0wjpfylpcd4rf/analytic-nt.pdf?dl=0">analytic-nt.pdf</a></li>
<li>Algebraic number theory, class field theory, and complex multiplication: <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/n0hgikez3nlfdui/ant.pdf?dl=0">ant.pdf</a></li>
</ul>
<p>For recent updates, please see the googledoc.</p>
<h2 id="high-school-math">High school math</h2>
<ul>
<li>Gliya geometry curriculum:
<ul>
<li>I wrote <a href="http://gliyanet.com/#!/nexus/math/Geometry">lessons</a> on introduction to geometry, angles, congruent triangles, similar triangles, constructions, and the angle bisector theorem. (Sorry, the link is currently not available.)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>High school math club materials: Materials I used for ERHS math club, 2007-2009.
<ul>
<li>Short-answer based
<ul>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/Sums%20and%20Products.pdf">Sums and products</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/Number%20Theory%20Part%20Two.pdf">Number theory</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/Triangles.doc">Triangles</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Proof-based
<ul>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/Box.pdf">Box principle</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/Strategies.pdf">Extremal, invariance, and induction</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/Algebra%20Proofs.doc">Inequalities</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/Combinatorial%20Proofs.doc">Combinatorics</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/Geometric%20Proofs.doc">Geometry</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Contests
<ul>
<li>“Pre-test” <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/contest001.jpg">part 1</a>, <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/contest001.jpg">part 2</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/End-of-Year-Contest.pdf">End of year contest</a> (the bunny problem has a simpler solution, see AwesomeMath UTD contest)</li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>AwesomeMath materials (<a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/source.zip">all source files</a>)
<ul>
<li>Algebra 3.5, 2010: I taught the second week at Santa Cruz. Notes below.
<ul>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/polynomials.pdf">Polynomials</a> (<a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/polynomials_solutions.pdf">solutions</a>) (Note that part of these notes appear in lectures 8 and ? in OMC.</li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/Inequalities.pdf">Inequalities</a>, <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/holder-minkowski.pdf">Holder and Minkowski</a>, <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/Inequalities%20strategies.pdf">strategies</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/functional.pdf">Functional equations</a> (<a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/functional_solutions.pdf">solutions</a>)</li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/exam2-sol.pdf">Week 2 exam</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/exam3.pdf">Final exam</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Team contest
<ul>
<li>2010, Dallas, <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2010-dallas-2.pdf">round 2</a> (<a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2010-dallas-2-sol.pdf">solutions</a>)</li>
<li>2010, Santa Cruz, <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2010-sc-1.pdf">round 1</a> (<a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2010-sc-1-sol.pdf">solutions</a>)</li>
<li>2010, Santa Cruz, <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2010-sc-2.pdf">round 2</a> (<a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2010-sc-2-sol.pdf">solutions</a>)</li>
<li>2010, Santa Cruz, <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2010-sc-3.pdf">round 3</a> (<a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2010-sc-3-sol.pdf">solutions</a>)</li>
<li>2011, Santa Cruz, <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2011-sc-2.pdf">round 2</a></li>
<li>2011, Santa Cruz, <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/high_school/awesome_math/2011-sc-3.pdf">round 3</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
<li>I wrote several lectures for Online Math Circle. <a href="https://github.com/holdenlee/omc">Source for all lectures</a>
<ul>
<li>Lecture 1: <a href="high_school/omc/1-beauty.pdf">The Beauty of Mathematics</a></li>
<li>Lecture 4: <a href="high_school/omc/cnt.pdf">Combinatorial Number Theory</a></li>
<li>Lecture 8: <a href="high_school/omc/poly1.pdf">Polynomials, Part 1</a></li>
<li>Lecture 11: <a href="high_school/omc/13-polynum.pdf">Complex Numbers</a></li>
<li>Lecture 13: <a href="high_school/omc/18-genfunc.pdf">Polynomials, Part 2</a> (Polynomials and number theory)</li>
<li>Lecture 18: <a href="high_school/omc/18-genfunc.pdf">Generating functions</a></li>
<li>Lecture 21 (with Yoni Miller): <a href="high_school/omc/21-pie.pdf">Principle of Inclusion and Exclusion</a></li>
<li>Lecture 23: <a href="high_school/omc/23-rearrange.pdf">Rearrangement inequality</a></li>
</ul></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="college-math">College math</h2>
<p>Various notes and homeworks I have written up for math subjects. Most of the source is available on <a href="https://github.com/holdenlee/mathnotes">github</a>, or given below. (There are also miscellanous notes there that are not listed below.)</p>
<p>See also this <a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1KZqXRf1xXlqQh_G-yG1DwgpUEmCo0DLVxe9_33eInQc/edit">googledoc</a> for notes on Part III classes by other students.</p>
<p>Note: the earlier notes are pdfs compiled from Word. I’ve given errata for them since the original word documents are corrupted and uneditable. Now I’ve learned better and use LaTeX instead.</p>
<ul>
<li>Algebra
<ul>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/linear_algebra.pdf">Linear algebra notes</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/abstract_algebra.pdf">Abstract algebra notes</a> (18.701-2)</li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/group_theory.pdf">Group theory</a> (18.701-2), some <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/college_math/Group%20Theory%20Problems%20with%20Solutions.pdf">problems with solutions</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Analysis
<ul>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/real_analysis.pdf">Real analysis</a> (18.100C), <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/real_analysis_errata.txt">errata</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/18125/notes.pdf">Measure theory</a> (18.125) (Note several sections in the latter half are incomplete.)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/uo5jgpteak379k9/part_iii_functional.pdf?dl=0">Functional analysis</a> (<a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/zqmyqe06s9zstrd/functional.zip?dl=0">source</a> (Part III, Fall 2013) (Ask me for a link to the ShareLaTeX.)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/kn8evd9ucztiek1/part_iii_distributions.pdf?dl=0">Distribution theory</a> (<a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/jtjgic4xbzj77qn/distributions.zip?dl=0">source</a>)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Geometry
<ul>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/18.965/main.pdf">Geometry of manifolds</a> (18.965)</li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/topology.pdf">Topology</a> (18.901), <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/topology_errata.txt">errata</a></li>
</ul></li>
<li>Combinatorics
<ul>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/18.318/main.pdf">Geometric graph theory</a> (18.318)</li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/18997/notes.pdf">Probabilistic methods</a> (18.997, spring 2011), <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/18997/psets.zip">problem sets</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/plrdg8oak90o0g2/part_iii_combo.pdf?dl=0">Extremal and probabilistic combinatorics</a> (Part III, Spring 2014)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/wob1sfwxffwznwm/noise_sensitivity.pdf?dl=0">Noise sensitivity</a> <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/6siohdavet0lnkb/ns.zip?dl=0">source</a> (Part III essay)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/6siohdavet0lnkb/ns.zip?dl=0">Ramsey theory</a> <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/10bymuecjvw5wlp/ramsey.zip?dl=0">source</a> (Part III, Fall 2013)</li>
<li><a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/177DqNun66BGiLKmOIPdOHeHf8lbcZUM7OHpNlsUY7Ho/edit#">Arithmetic combinatorics</a> (Part III, Fall 2013)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/tkkgwcrcxxecuhk/part_iii_equidistribution.pdf?dl=0">Additive combinatorics and equidistribution</a> <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/foqhbttmqyqu2yo/ed.zip?dl=0">source</a> (Part III, Spring 2014)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/85csggziyk983sl/AMiIT_review.pdf?dl=0">Algebraic methods in incidence theory</a> <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/nmr10deid4wwvno/AMiIT.zip?dl=0">source</a> (Part III, Spring 2014)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Computer science
<ul>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/18.404/main.pdf">Theory of computation</a> (18.404)</li>
</ul></li>
<li>Number theory
<ul>
<li>Additive number theory (18.784) <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/18784/Finite%20field%20Waring.pdf">final paper</a> on finite field Waring’s problem</li>
<li>Automorphic forms (18.785) <a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/18785/psets.zip">psets</a></li>
<li><a href="http://holdenlee.github.io/coursework/math/18.787/main.pdf">Abelian varieties and p-divisible groups</a> (18.787) (warning: poorly edited)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/t1c08591cs5otfb/part_iii_elliptic.pdf?dl=0">Elliptic curves</a> <a href="https://www.dropbox.com/s/pw8wd3oiiti6krs/elliptic.zip?dl=0">source</a> (Part III, Fall 2013)</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Is A-Fu Stupid</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Is%20A-Fu%20Stupid.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Is%20A-Fu%20Stupid.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Is A-Fu Stupid </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/pbible.html">pbible</a>, <a href="/tags/parable.html">parable</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>阿芙傻嗎？</p>
<p>“Look, A-Fu is so stupid. We give him a choice between two pennies and a dime, and every time he chooses two pennies. Here, A-Fu, would you rather have two pennies or a dime? See? He chose the pennies! How stupid is A-Fu!”</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>
<entry>
    <title>Ideal vs institutionalized</title>
    <link href="http://holdenlee.github.io/Ideal%20vs%20institutionalized.html" />
    <id>http://holdenlee.github.io/Ideal%20vs%20institutionalized.html</id>
    <published>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2017-08-13T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <summary type="html"><![CDATA[
<div class="container">

  <div id="content">
    <div class="page header">
      <h1> Ideal vs institutionalized </h1>
    </div>
    
    
    <div class="info">
      
       
        <p>Posted: 2017-08-13 
          , Modified: 2017-08-13 
	</p>
      
       <p>Tags: <a href="/tags/society.html">society</a>, <a href="/tags/dichotomy.html">dichotomy</a>, <a href="/tags/language.html">language</a>, <a href="/tags/social.html">social</a>, <a href="/tags/values.html">values</a></p> 
       <p>Parent: <a href="/Views.html">Views</a></p> 
	   <p>Children: </p> 
    </div>
    
    
  </div>
  <!--/div-->

  <div class="toc"></div>

  <div class="blog-main">
    <p>What’s it mean to be socially adept, or well-adjusted socially? I’ve looked upon the word “social” with disdain, but maybe my lack of value-belief in it is because the “social” has been translated badly into my personal vocabulary. It’s another word like feminism or religion or altruism that means different things in the ideal and the institutionalized sense.</p>
<p>What do I mean by this?</p>
<ul>
<li>One of the main goals of <strong>religion</strong> is to encourage people to <a href="http://www.npr.org/2014/12/19/371688189/how-can-we-make-the-world-more-compassionate">be more compassionate</a> towards others. However, in the modern world, “religion” is often used to draw boundaries between people and to make moral judgments on people. (See also my post on <a href="Personalized%20spirituality.html">personalized spirituality</a>.)</li>
<li><p>Letitia Baldrige, an expert in manners and <strong>etiquette</strong> says the following: </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Etiquette is the set of techniques you use to have great manners. Manners are the way you want to behave, and the way you want to make people feel. Etiquette is the granularization of that desire to treat people with grace and warmth.&quot; (from <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/22669010-a-curious-mind?ac=1&amp;from_search=1">A Curious Mind</a>, p. 88)</p>
</blockquote>
However, etiquette makes me think of rules that are rigidly followed by an “in-group” to put them in a higher class than an “out-group.”</li>
<li>Most people would agree with <strong>feminism</strong> if it’s framed as the general idea that women should have equal opportunities as men, but they may not agree with the practices of specific feminist movements.</li>
<li><p><strong>Altruism</strong> is almost by definition a good thing, but it’s gotten a <a href="https://www.goodreads.com/book/show/24611937-strangers-drowning?ac=1&amp;from_search=1">bad rep in recent years</a> because people are afraid of moralists who want to take a moral high ground over other people. (Note that it’s easy for values, in going from an ideal to an institutionalized setting, to be hijacked by the tribal instinct - to draw boundaries between ourselves and other people.)</p></li>
</ul>
<p>“Social” got translated into my personal vocabulary as show-show, and it’s been about projecting a kind of persona. That was the impression that people gave me when then talk about being social, and from my own thought that I have to act different around other people.</p>
<p>But maybe the right, ideal-version of social is, how can I make other people feel comfortable, and have interesting connections/learning exchanges with them? That is the ideal social and the institutionalized social is projecting “I’m a funny, cool, interesting person that everyone wants to gather around” at a cocktail party. When I say “I don’t care about being social” I mean I don’t want to be institutionalized-social, but I do want to be ideal-social. In this way ideal-social is closer than institutionalized-social to a lot of other values like kindness, open-mindedness, and learning that I hold important.</p>
<p>So my personal definitions of very abstract words like “social” are important, because each such word is no one thing but a circle of concepts, and what I determine as the core essence of the word taints that whole circle of concepts. If I determine it’s negative, then I discount the related concepts even though they’re good, and the opposite if it’s positive.</p>

  </div>
  
    

    <!-- Extension : Sharing buttons @ www.sharethis.com -->
    <span class='st_facebook_large' displayText='Facebook'></span>
    <span class='st_twitter_large' displayText='Tweet'></span>
    <span class='st_googleplus_large' displayText='Google +'></span>
    <span class='st_reddit_large' displayText='Reddit'></span>
    <span class='st__large' displayText=''></span>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    


  
    <script>!function(d,s,id){var js,fjs=d.getElementsByTagName(s)[0],p=/^http:/.test(d.location)?'http':'https';if(!d.getElementById(id)){js=d.createElement(s);js.id=id;js.src=p+'://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js';fjs.parentNode.insertBefore(js,fjs);}}(document, 'script', 'twitter-wjs');</script>
  </div>
  
  
</div>
]]></summary>
</entry>

</feed>
